What we want to talk about now is, when kicking an extra point or a field goal, you want to have the proper kicking mechanisms.
What we're talking about first of all is, obviously, balance.
When you approach the ball to kick a field goal, you do not want to be leaned over.
If you lean over you can't get good leg extension.
You'll only be able to kick your leg up as high as you're bent over and that won't allow you to kick it very far.
You also don't want to be on your back foot.
When you plant you don't want to be leaning backward or you'll kick the ball straight up in the air.
So, it takes a lot of good balance.
John's going to demonstrate.
You see he has his body straight up and when he kicks through watch how high his leg extension is when he kicks through (video demo).
He has good mechanics, he has his body open, when he comes through he explodes the leg through, he keeps it straight and he kicks it up as high as he possibly can.
You can see if he was bent over he would not have been able to get that leg extension.
It's all about kicking the ball and getting the most out of your body when you make the kick.
We're going to see what it looks like at full speed.
Watch his balance as he approaches, in the way he kicks his leg through and up, and how he gets good height when he kicks the ball through (video demo).
You can see his balance as he comes through.
Everything was straight, everything was exploding through the ball, very good and balanced.